Guide to the Ulrich Bonnell Phillips Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Manuscripts, 1904-1939; Series XVI
  - Phillips, Ulrich Bonnell
    - True History of the Civil War, 1904 (Box 34, Folder 340)
    - Twentieth Century Cotton Plantations, 1904 (Box 34, Folder 341)
    - Plantations as Civilizing Factor, 1904 (Box 34, Folder 342)
    - Reviews: Wright, Reed, Dyer, 1906 (Box 34, Folder 343)
    - Origin and Growth of Black Belts, 1906 (Box 34, Folder 344)
    - Introduction to Plantation and Frontier, 1910 (Box 34, Folder 345)
    - The South in the Building of the Nation, 1909-1910 (Box 34, Folder 346)
    - The Economics of Slavery, 1815-1860, 1912 (Box 34, Folder 347)
    - The Literary Movement for Secession, 1914 (Box 34, Folder 348)
    - A Jamaica Slave Plantation, 1914 (Box 34, Folder 349)
    - Slave Crime in Virginia, 1915 (Box 34, Folder 350)
    - Black Labor, Slave and Free, 1915 (Box 34, Folder 351)
    - Plantations with Slave Labor and Free, 1925 (Box 34, Folder 352)
    - An Antique Plantation, 1769-1818, 1926 (Box 34, Folder 353)
    - Reviews: Sears, Catterall, Malone, 1926-1927 (Box 34, Folder 354)
    - Florida Plantation Records, 1-42, 1927 (Box 34, Folder 355)
    - The Central Theme of Southern History, 1928 (Box 34, Folder 356)
    - John Caldwell Calhoun, 1929 (Box 34, Folder 357)
    - Review: Thomason, Jeb Stuart, 1930 (Box 34, Folder 358)
    - Negroes of The Sudan, 1930 (Box 34, Folder 359)
    - William Harris Crawford, 1930 (Box 34, Folder 360)
    - Notes taken on African trip, 1929-1930 (Box 35, Folder 361)
    - The Historic Defense of Negro Slavery, 1931 (Box 35, Folder 362)
    - Reviews: Carpenter, Johnson, Twelve Southerners, Odum, and Mitchell, 1931 (Box 35, Folder 363)
    - Memorial Day Address at Yale, 1931 (Box 35, Folder 364)
    - Plantations East and South of Suez, 1931 (Box 35, Folder 365)
    - The Perennial Negro, 1931 (Box 35, Folder 366)
    - Southern Arguments on Secession, 1931 (Box 35, Folder 367)
    - Reviews: W.J. de Renne Catalogue, Abernathy, 1932 (Box 35, Folder 368)
    - Reviews: Adams, Vance, 1932, 1933 (Box 35, Folder 369)
    - Popular Sovereignty and Slavery, Modern, 1934 (Box 35, Folder 370)
    - Alexander Hamilton Stephens, 1935 (Box 35, Folder 371)
    - Robert Augustus Toombs, 1936 (Box 35, Folder 372)
    - Daughters of England, 1939 (Box 35, Folder 373)
    - The Fire-eaters, 1939 (Box 35, Folder 374)
    - Political Combinations in Georgia, Circa 1900-1901 (Box 35, Folder 375)
    - The South in the Building of the Nation, Circa 1916 (Box 35, Folder 376)
    - Southern Reaction to Nullification, Circa 1921 (Box 35, Folder 377)
    - Traits and Contributions of F. J. Turner, Undated (Box 35, Folder 378)
    - The Trustee Colony and Preface, Undated (Box 35, Folder 379)
    - Unpublished manuscripts, Undated (Box 35, Folder 380)
  - Others
    - Crossman, L.E., Undated (Box 36, Folder 381)
    - Dumond, Dwight Lowell, 1926 (Box 36, Folder 382)
    - Munn, J. Burrus, 1914 (Box 36, Folder 383)
    - Reed, John C., Undated (Box 36, Folder 384)
    - Student notes, 1903-1904 (Box 36, Folder 385-386)
    - Student papers, Undated (Box 36, Folder 387)
- Research notes, Undated; Series XVII
  This series contains Phillips's unorganized three by five inch research note cards on subjects relating to U.S. and Southern history. Note cards in this series are undated.
  - Notes (Box 37)
  - Notes (Box 38)
  - Notes (Box 39)
  - Notes (Box 40)
  - Notes (Box 41)
  - Notes (Box 42)
  - Notes (Box 43)
  - Notes (Box 44)
- Miscellanea, 1750-1931; Series XVIII
  This series contains a box of lantern slides relating to Southern history, clippings of newspaper and journal articles reflecting the work of Phillips, photographs complimenting Phillips's writings on Southern history, and printed ephemera and manuscripts unrelated to materials in other series.
  This series is arranged by record type: Lantern slides, Clippings, Photographs, Other material.
  - Lantern slides, Undated (Box 45)
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Alternate Formats: All of these images have been digitally reproduced in the Manuscripts and Archives Digital Image Database (MADID).
    Conditions Governing Access
    Access to the original glass negatives and slides is restricted. Researchers must use digital images in MADID.
  - Clippings, 1903-1931 (Box 46)
  - Photographs, Undated (Box 46)
  - Other material
    - Manuscripts, 1750-1907 and undated (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Posters and broadsides, 1812-1907 and undated (Box 47, Folder 3)
      General
      See also: box 4, folder 81
      - Campaign flag for Henry Clay and Theodore Frelinghuysen, 1844 (Box 48)
      - Rebel War Claims poster, 1876 (Box 48)
    - Printed material
      - General: circulars, miscellanea, 1800-1886, 1922 and undated (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1851-1898 and undated (Box 47, Folder 5)
- Additional material, Circa 1900-circa 1930; Accession 2007-M-012
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred from the Peabody Museum of Natural History, Yale University, 2006.
  This accession contains photographs, glass negatives, stereoscopic photographs, and a small amount of printed ephemera documenting the southeastern United States, especially South Carolina and Louisiana, during the first part of the twentieth century. Subjects depicted included blacks, both casually and at work; city and rural life; and work activity in cotton and sugar cane fields. Photographs also document buildings, including cabins, slave quarters, plantation homes, farms, and cities. Most of the photographs are undated and are circa 1900-circa 1930 unless more specific dates are noted at the file level below. Some of the photographs are annotated with plate numbers and appear to have been used as illustrations in Phillips's books.
  This accession is arranged by type of material; photographs are arranged alphabetically by topic.
  Alternate Formats: Some of the photographic materials in this accession have been digitally reproduced in the Manuscripts and Archives Digital Image Database.
  - Postcards of the South (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photographic reproductions of engravings depicting plantation life (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photographs
    - Baptisms (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Blacks (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Blacks working (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Buildings (rural) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Cabins and slave quarters (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Camp Gordon, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Chain gangs (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Cotton industry (Box 1, Folder 10-13)
    - H. C. Hall photographs of the South (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Additional photographs (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Homes (city) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Homes (farm) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Logging (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Nature (unidentified locations) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Plantations (Box 2, Folder 6-8)
      Includes photographs of The Oaks, a plantation near the Cooper River in South Carolina.
    - Scenes (city) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Scenes (farm) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Trees and scenery (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Turner, Frederick J. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Wharves (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Printed ephemera, Circa 1900-1937 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Includes an offprint of Wiley, B. I., "Vicissitudes of Early Reconstruction Farming in the Lower Mississippi Valley," Journal of Southern History 3:4 (1937 Nov).
  - Stereoscopic photographs of New Orleans by S. T. Blessing (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Congo negatives, 1929 January; 14 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Alternate Format: Twelve of these negatives have been digitally reproduced in the Manuscripts and Archives Digital Image Database (MADID).
  - Glass negatives and slides of the south, 30 (Box 4)
    These negatives and slides represent twenty-eight different images (two are duplicates). Eleven of the glass slides in this box duplicate lantern slides in Series XVIII, box 45.
    Alternate Format: All of these images have been digitally reproduced in the Manuscripts and Archives Digital Image Database (MADID).
  - Preservation masters of nitrate negatives, Approximately 50 computer files (TIFF) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Includes images of people, black and white; rural scenes; plantations; city buildings; and interiors.
    Alternate Format: All of these images have been digitally reproduced in the Manuscripts and Archives Digital Image Database (MADID). Search for "nitrate negatives" to retrieve them.
    Separated Materials
    Original nitrate negatives were removed from the collection and destroyed following digitization.
    General note
    Contact Public Services (phone: 203 432-1735, e-mail: mssa.reference@yale.edu) for information regarding access to the TIFF image files.